Dr. Khalifa:
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
We seek refuge in God from Satan.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
Tonight, we're starting at Sura 54,
55, excuse me.
And our teacher tonight will be Laurie, right?
But before we start, I want to make some corrections.
In my Khutba today, I make some boo-boos
sometimes.
Sometimes I say things that appear to be not
very tactful.
For example, we have here a great team of
cake-bringers or cake-makers.
And when I asked, then Rahima was... it was Rahima's turn, Laurie's
turn, I said "the best."
So, this... they're all, they're all great makers of cakes, bringers
of cakes.
And this appears not to be tactful, but I
have to explain to you that each believer is the best.
So, when I, when I say "the best," I'm referring to every
single one of them.
Because we're all...
I hope I don't make it worse.
No, honest, I, because you people are so special
that every one of you is the best.
And when I say that, I just want to pay you the highest possible compliment without infringing on the others' properties.
But they all are the best, each one of them.
Every single...
Did I describe your cake as the best when
you brought it in?
Now how do I get out of this one?
Help!
I think I'll get out by saying "okay, take it
over, Laurie."
Laurie:
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
I take refuge in God from Satan the rejected.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[55:1]  GOD, Most Gracious.
[55:2]  The One who teaches the Quran.
[55:3]  The One who created the human beings.
[55:4]  The One who taught him how to distinguish right from wrong.
[55:5]  The sun and the moon created his timing devices
[55:6]  The stars and the trees prostrate.
[55:7]  He raised the heaven and established the balance.
[55:8]  You shall not transgress when you weigh.
[55:9]  You shall be equitable when you weigh; do not cheat when you trade.
[55:10]  He made the earth for all the people.
[55:11]  With fruits, and palms sheath.
[55:12]  With food grains and flowers.
[55:13]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:14]  He created the human from clay, like the potter's.
[55:15]  And created the jinns from blazing fire.
[55:16]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:17]  Lord of the two easts and the two wests.
[55:18]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:19]  He separates the fresh water from the salt water.
[55:20]  Between them is a barrier they cannot surmount.
[55:21]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:22]  From the two seas you extract pearls and coral.
[55:23]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:24]  He controls the ships that roam the sea like flags.
[55:25]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:26]  Everyone on earth will perish.
[55:27]  But the presence of your Lord will continue. He is the Possessor of Majesty and Honor.
[55:28]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:29]  Everyone in the heavens and the earth implores Him. Every day He is in full control.
[55:30]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:31]  We will deal with both of you, the two entities, humans and jinns.
[55:32]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:33]  O you jinns and humans, if you can penetrate the outer limits of the heavens and the earth, then penetrate. You can only penetrate when given authority.
[55:34]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:35]  You will be bombarded with masses of fire and molten metal, and you can never succeed.
[55:36]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
Dr. Khalifa: Are you checking the tape, David?
This is why we should be checking them.
Do the same thing over there.
(unintelligible) has grown up enough now.
Take good care of him.
Laurie: This chapter is very special to me, because
I have this weakness that I'm very impatient
with knowledge, and if I don't know something,
I can't grasp it.
And it always caused me trouble in school,
because if I didn't understand it, I couldn't do anything about it.
And I became Muslim, and I read the Quran, and I found out that I had to submit, even though I didn't understand something.
It was really a test for me, because I just
wanted to know.
And I never understood the jinns. I wish like... And I read it and I knew that they...
Thank you.
And I knew because it was in the Quran. I had to believe it, but I didn't know what they were, and nobody could explain it to me.
You know, and I got really wild explanations of what
the jinns were.
And it always troubled me, but I just forced
myself to submit.
And in
the second chapter of the Quran, where it says that
"the believers are those who believe
in the unseen." And this was part of the unseen.
And I knew that, IN SHAA ALLAH, over time, that
God would explain it to me.
And one of the blessings of being in this
mosque is having things explained to us.
And as Rashad said in the Khutba today, it's a mercy from God that He sends a messenger from among us to explain to us.
The knowledge is here in the Quran, and all
of us have read the Quran.
You know, I read it once a month, from front
to back.
And every time there's something new.
And we get what we need at the time we need
it.
And we in this mosque are just developing
so far. It's just amazing.
You know, Rashad and Lisa and Hasan went
to Canada, and there were the people believed they way we do.
They're still way behind us in the knowledge, because we're here every Friday night, learning and studying.
We have the input of all these believers here.
And we have a messenger that is given the
knowledge that is passed on to us.
And we're responsible for the information
in the Quran.
And, you know, the verse in the Quran that
was admonishing the (unintelligible), saying that
they were believers when they weren't really.
They were just submitters, and that's the first step.
But only the believers can attain Paradise.
So, if we don't have absolute certainty, we
can't ever grow and develop to our fullest extent.
And that's where the increased knowledge is
that should bless me.
And I read, you know, I've read this verse
so many times, and the first time I read it,
you too, the humans and the jinns, you know,
I just didn't understand what it meant.
I didn't understand what the jinns were, what
their role was, what they had to do with me or with us.
It was just a mystery. And I just, you know, like I said, I had to
force myself not to question it, not to be hung up about it.
When we had that discussion about jinns in the Quranic studies, I just kept my mouth shut, you know, very different things.
But now, just in this last year, we found
out what this is, and so this chapter has a totally different meaning.
And for the first time, I understand what
it means.
And we know now that the jinns are, you know,
they have the same requirements.
There's other verses in the Quran that they
have the same requirements that we do.
Some of them believed in Jesus, and they believed
in other things, and then they heard the Quran,
and they believed, and, you know, they have
the same requirements that we do.
And they also have the same rewards that we
do.
You know, there are entities that we can't see. You know, we don't know. They can see us, but we can't see them.
And yet, the Heaven that's described here
in later verses is for them, too.
They have their own, but it's the same set-up as ours. It's exactly the same for them.
Like, you know, these creatures that are so
important in this scripture that we don't know anything about.
And now we know that the jinns were those
that, before creation, sided with Satan and
took a stand against God and believed that Satan could be a god besides God, that God could have partners, which is the ultimate blasphemy.
And they were banished, and they have a
chance to redeem themselves as well.
And our job is to, you know, and I used to
read about Satan and his troops
and generations of jinns and humans, that I didn't know, how
do they, how do they come to be generations?
How do they multiply? How do they, you know, what do they do to
reproduce themselves?
Now we know that a jinn is assigned to
each one of us, and so their reproduction is,
it coincides with our reproduction, that
each one of us is given a companion at
the time of our entry into this world, and we're
in the same boat. We both sinned.
We both came to this earth with original sin.
We both took a stand against God, the jinns
more forcefully than we did, but we took the same stand
as not being for God, because there's
only two ways.
Either you're for or you're against, and we
were wishy-washy, but basically we were against God.
We've both been given the chance to redeem ourselves.
Thing is, the jinns took the definite stand. So, they're going to try to convert us to Satan's way of thinking and to the original sin that we committed.
So, we have to convert them.
So from the time of birth, we're in this constant
struggle with our jinn companion to convert them to righteousness
and to protect ourselves
from falling into the path of the jinn.
And It's a struggle. It's a struggle every day of our lives, and
it just goes on and on.
And the blessing about knowing who your enemy
is, is knowing what they are, what their goal is,
what their tactics are, so you can learn
how to defend yourself.
And that's what the Quran is, and that's where
these blessings come from.
So, we know that.
And to me, the greatest blessing of all is
knowing that we do have original sin and we're bad.
You know, we were born bad, because we took the stand
against God.
So now that we know that, we know what we
have to do.
We have to, just every day of our lives, try
to redeem ourselves from that sin.
And the Quran is very specific about giving
us the way to do it, and we know now,
we've heard it several times in Khutbas, that we have
to ask ourselves every day "who is my god this week?"
Ok. Because that's our only goal in life, is to
redeem ourselves. Nothing else has any importance whatsoever.
And we have to do certain things. We have to support ourselves. We have to take care of ourselves. But
with the goal in mind that this is to do righteousness, you know, we can't be a burden to society, we can't steal, so we have to work and support ourselves.
So, it's all in tune with the same thing, which
is purifying ourselves, and growing and developing our souls.
So as soon as you take that stand, then the
jinns are going to try to,
your companion and others are going to try and make you stray
away from that path.
And the greater the stand you take, the greater the enticements are going to be, and you just have to be prepared.
And I've talked to several people who've said
that they've encountered the same thing I
did when I made the stand, that I was going
to really try and devote more of my thoughts
to God because I wasn't doing enough, and
I knew it, that they just took over,
and they didn't want me to, even the little that I
was doing was in danger of not being done at all.
It's just a constant struggle.
And so I know this now, and I know that I
have to just be on the alert at all times for, for this. And we know that
most of it is sneaky whispering.
And there's even a Sura where, you know, this is
devoted to this, that Satan whispers to us, I mean, little
things that don't seem so bad.
You know, we've talked about this before. "Oh, you can
wait until the game is over before you pray" or
you know "I'll pray later," and then something happens
and you don't pray.
And that time can never be regained. Once you miss the Prayer, you can't make it up. That time is...
The inhabitants of Hell are the farthest from
God on the Day of Judgment.
Knowing that Heaven is close to God, they
will leave Hell and sneak into the area closer to God,
but because they are not sufficiently
prepared to come close to God,
they will suffer terribly in the presence of God and will flee
back to Hell and so on forever.
Here's this vicious circle that they're
in.
A man: It's just like the Jehovah's Witnesses now.
They don't believe in Hell, but they
believe 144,000 go to Heaven and the remainder
of their chosen people or whatever go to Paradise. But they still deny Hell.
They say "there's no burning Hell. There's no
none of this. You just no longer exist,"
which is a lie of... outright lying itself, because
nothing that exists can be destroyed.
You know, like matter can't be created or
destroyed, ever destroyed. It just recycles.
In the real world that we're in. No, in the other
world, this is not the real world, but in the world we're in now.
So, they don't believe in Hell, because if
you tell them anything contrary to anything pleasant after death,
they say "well, we just
don't exist anymore."
"Well, we never get punished for what we do
wrong."
"And that's our punishment, not existing."
"Well, we can get a reward. If we're real good,
we get this reward."
"But if we're real bad, we just don't exist
anymore."
"Just have a reward and no punishment."
Dr. Khalifa: They wish, they wish this.
A man: That's what I'm saying. This, this is...
A woman: Thank you.
Dr. Khalifa: Quran...
A man: This is what I thought about it.
Dr. Khalifa: The Quran says 'they will wish that they..."
A man: Yeah. "This is the Hell they used to deny."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: They deny Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: I just wanna add here something that we
should all know.
I know Laurie knows that but she just didn't mention it yet.
It has to do with the looks.
See, verse 40 says, (unintelligible), number 39.
Where's the...
Well, not they ask...Oh, 39, yeah.
"The humans and the jinn will not be asked
about their sins."
Nobody will need to ask anybody about anything,
because the believers develop their souls,
and the disbelievers fail to develop their
souls.
And in Sura 17, we're told that the differences
in the Hereafter are...
In this room, the differences in our sizes
are within a few inches.
But in the Hereafter, the difference will be like the difference between a mouse and the city of New York, city of Tucson, let's say.
So, when you see somebody the size of the city
of Tucson, he or she has developed the soul sufficiently.
This is why they will be able to come closer
to God.
When you see somebody's the size of a mouse,
you don't need to ask, you know "what did you do wrong?"
So, that is, this is why nobody will need to ask anybody
about their sins.
It is so obvious.
There'll be no question.
Also, in Sura 17, we're told that everybody
will be the judge for him or herself, to herself.
Because in that dimension, we will see what we really look like, how much we really developed or how much we lacked development.
So, only ones that are guilty will be recognized by their looks.
They'll be undeveloped. They'll be shrunken,
like being born without arms and legs.
Deformed.
They will be born into the Hereafter, deformed,
undeveloped, aborted.
But they'll be alive, very well, I mean, well, very alive, not well.
Also, God lets us understand, as Lori explained in verse 44, how they will try to sneak into Heaven, and they'll find it worse than Hell.
They will sneak into the Lower Heaven, and they will find it worse than Hell, because they cannot stand, come any closer to God.
See, God left it completely up to us, completely.
This is why God does not inflict an atom's
weight of injustice.
It's absolutely up to you.
You can be as close to God as you want, in
the High Heaven, or you can be as far from God as you want.
It's completely up to us.
So, the conclusion is that God does not put
a single person in Hell.
It is the people who insist or choose, and they
insist on going to Hell.
This, the whole thing will be automatic in the
Hereafter.
This is why it is important to do, for example,
the five Prayers a day.
You don't do the five Prayers every day,
you are in trouble.
That's the minimum that you can do.
Because those are the meals for the real person.
Imagine if you don't feel... your body does not dry, and you
don't feed your body for two months.
What will your body look like?
There's no death in the Hereafter.
Just imagine not eating for two months.
And the people out there in the street, they
don't feed their soul for years and years and years.
And imagine what they look like. Can you imagine what they look like?
Just look into our dimension here and think
of bodies that didn't eat for years.
You see those skeletal pictures of the starving
people in Central Africa, Ethiopia, Sudan.
What they look like, you can see their ribs.
The shrunk skin and bones.
And this happens to the soul if the soul is
not fed the five meals every day.
[55:41]  The guilty will be recognized by their looks;...
You can tell who is starving in Africa and
who is not.
By looking at them.
And in the Hereafter, you will be able to
know who is starving and who is not.
Except it will be by choice.
So, now we go back to Lori and number 46,
The Higher Heaven.
Lori: Yes.
[55:46]  For those who reverence the glory of their Lord, there will be two Paradises.
[55:47]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:48]  With abundant vegetation.
[55:49]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:50]  Two springs run freely therein.
[55:51]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:52]  They will have two kinds of every fruit.
[55:53]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:54]  They will relax on furnishings lined with
silk while the fruits of the two gardens are brought near.
[55:55]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:56]  They will have magnificent spouses therein,
never before touched by any human or jinn.
[55:57]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:58]  They will look like gems and coral.
[55:59]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
[55:60]  Is the reward of righteousness anything but
the best blessing?
[55:61]  Which of your Lord's marvels can you two deny?
These verses are just so beautiful.
The Higher Heaven, and we know that the verses
describing Heaven and Hell are allegorical
because there's no way that we can conceive
or understand what it really will be like
until God gives us these things that brings it into
our own dimension.
But we know that there are stratifications.
And for those, very clear here,
[55:46]  For those who reverence the glory of their Lord,...
who've done everything that they have been
able to do, developed their souls,
who have kept the commandments, who have not
set up another god besides God, then God rewards
those with the best blessings.
And He doesn't even have to do it.
But there's a verse in Quran that says
that God is appreciative.
And it's just, that's so incredible to me
because He doesn't need us at all.
Why should He be appreciative of anything
that we do?
It's just that He is Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
And we can't comprehend. We can't comprehend
that kind of mercy because we're bound by our own
selfishness and, you know, our own
desire to succeed and our own concern with our own well-being.
We can't imagine that something could be so gracious and so merciful that it could just provide all these things for us.
I mean, it's just the ultimate of just leisure,
not having to do anything
and everything that you want, every kind of food
that you want to eat, and you don't have to do anything.
It's just, you know, the springs, they're
running freely and you don't have to worry about
finding a spouse and going through all
these changes.
And you know, they're just there and you don't
have to do anything at all.
It's just, it's just an incredible mercy.
And, you know, what did we have to do in this
life to get there?
I mean, it's like the most incredible, you
know, if somebody offered you a deal and said
"if you, you know, buy stock at, you know, 50 cents a share and in
10 years, it'll sell for a million dollars a share"
and you think, you know, that's impossible.  How could anything like that exist?
But this is even greater.
All we had to do was say our five Prayers every day, not to have any other gods besides God, but just for our own benefit anyway.
God doesn't need us.
You know, to do the religious duties that
are so simple, to fast for one month,
which if we know is good for us, it lowers our blood
pressure, it, you know, gives our kidneys a break.
We know that praying is good for us.
You know, we know about lubricating the joints, and
combating arthritis.
All of these things that are done for our benefit anyway, and just
in exchange for doing that, we get this unbelievable,
you know, this Paradise that, you know, is beyond our
wildest dreams, and we know that it's even greater than this.
Because this is just something
that God gives us, which is to our limited ability to
to perceive anything. What God has
in store for us is so much greater.
In fact, we're told in the Quran that
we can't even imagine what is in store for us
as a reward for doing what we're supposed
to do in the first place.
It's just incredible mercy.
And, you know, we've talked about this before
sometimes, well, you know.
The Lower Heaven isn't that bad either, when we read the next
verses you'll see, but
the picture here, I mean, there's not that great a differences that
we know
that the Higher Heaven just means that we'll be closer
to God.
And that's the only understanding that we really need to have, is that we'll be closer to God.
And the further away from Him we are, the more miserable we'll be.
So, even though we'll be in Paradise in the
Lower Heaven, it won't be the same.
And in the next verses, the Lower Heaven,
starting with 62.
Dr. Khalifa: Next, the next two verses, IN SHAA ALLAH, will tell us who goes
to the Higher Heaven and who goes to Lower Heaven.
Very specific.
And our teacher will be Naghemeh.
Friday.
Sura 56, Naghmeh. (unintelligible)
Before this...
A woman: Yula asked that if you would pray for her
son.
Dr. Khalifa: It's Yula?
A woman: He has this virus thing and really a bad cough and
stuff. She said she had to take him right now.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Nothing bad will happen to her, IN SHAA ALLAH.
We will recite Al-Fãtehah for Yula and her baby.
And we recite Al-Fãtehah for also, ask God to heal Lori, her voice.
And Parivash's daughter, Lamia, is having
an operation of teeth next week on Friday.
God loves it when we pray to Him and ask Him
to heal our friend and heal us.
And ask Him for the dearest wish.
Also, we're gonna pray to God to bless
the birthday folks, Soad, Hamid.
Hamid's birthday is tomorrow.
And Soad's birthday is on 7th.
And the Erishen's are having an anniversary, the 19th anniversary, I think. No?
So, ask God to give them all the greatest year coming up and every year after that to be even better with God's blessings.
Al-Fãtehah
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)
Arrahman Arraheem (1:3)
Maliki Yawm Eddeen (1:4)
Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Ehdina Al-Serata Al-Mustaqeem (1:6)
Serata Al-Lazeena An’amta ‘Alayhim Ghayri Al-Maghdoobi ‘Alayhim Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
Also, we ask God to bless (unintelligible). Keep our friend forever.
Audience: IN SHAA ALLAH
Naghmeh: From far ahead.
Okay.
We know...
Naghmeh: Really, should I repeat this?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Naghmeh: Oh, Okay.
Okay, God says "and those who are far ahead
will be far ahead."
And they will be closest to God.
And far ahead is, of course, the Highest Heaven.
Then, and we know that far ahead doesn't mean how
much money you have or what looks you have
or how much education you've got.
But it means, what, the kind of intelligence that
you have within where you see God and the truth and righteousness.
And, and we know that that's what puts us far ahead.
Not because, like I was saying earlier, that
there are a lot of people who have all those things.
And they feel like they have a lot of power
and they're in control.
But they are very miserable.
And they go through drugs and alcohol.
Most of the people who are out there that
are into drugs and alcohol are doctors, people that we go to help us,
people who make all that money and who are
in the high parts of society.
And people who think they are in control.
Not that every doctor is bad or anything like
that. But the power has a lot of times led to trouble.
Because people are not righteous enough. And they don't see.
And they don't open their hearts. And they don't let go of that ego enough to understand that if you use your power with God's will,
then maybe you'll get somewhere. But other than that, you don't get anywhere.
Maybe here for a while. Like God says "I'll let them enjoy this life
for a while." But just for a while.
And, then we know that there are people who don't
have those things.
Yet their lives are very calm and very fulfilled.
And also, as I was saying earlier, is that the Quran has taught us that God is in full control of our money, of what we look like,
of what we, of how our lives are the thread that we walk
into our lives.
And, then it seems pretty unfair that God would choose some people to have money and looks and put them in Heaven because of that.
But what makes more sense is that God has
given every one of us, no matter what standards we have,
He has given us that freedom of choice, which makes us equal.
And makes us the wise ones if we seek to choose
the right path.
And, and that's where we'll be if we do the commandments
in the Quran.
If the people of Jesus or Moses' time did
everything that they brought down through the Bible or the Torah.
And, and if they did those things, then they will
be in the Far Heaven.
And of course we know that this is the most
complete.
The prayers and the fasting and the charity, and belief in God alone and the Hereafter, and working righteousness.
And, and God willing, that will put us far ahead
and make us sovereigns on earth,
no matter how much money or anything we have.
And a lot of times I think that's really hard
to understand.
And a lot of times we get bogged down. I know I do.
Like when I see someone, you know, who has cute clothes
on her, that's really pretty or something like that.
And, and you just have to step back and think and say "that's not important. You have what God thought was good for you."
God says that you'll be
[56:12]  In the gardens of bliss.
[56:13]  Multitudes from the early generations.
Gardens of bliss is of course Heaven.
We have a footnote that says "the early generations of Muslims were characterized by following the Quran, the whole Quran, and nothing but the Quran.
250 years after the Prophet, Hadith and Sunnah appeared, followed by the various schools of jurisprudence.
This marked the progressive deterioration
of the Muslim nation."
Ok. This tells us "the early generations," those are the people that had the big prophets. Those are the ones who had the messengers
that... well, we have messengers, too, but it just
seems like there then it seemed like it was more in people's lives.
Now, it seems like technology has taken our
lives so much that people don't think about
God actually sending angels down or messengers
down or miracles down.
But... So, those people who did follow the exact correct
way were in the early generations and there are some people now.
But right now it seems like we just need more and more and more proof to make us be disciplined enough to understand.
And, and it seems like as time has gone by, people
just want to interpret the way they think.
They don't like something the way it sounds. They have to change it to the way they want it.
And that just makes a lot of conflict. And thank God that's why we have the Quran, which is so easy to understand.
And God says it's easy to memorize and understand.
And, and it says in the footnote that "250 years
after the Prophet, these two books appeared."
And we know that these two books are the books that have all the traditions, the things that are totally contradictory to the Quran.
And these people are so blind that they don't
even sit down to compare, to understand and see
that it is contradictory to what their Prophet that they idolize brought down.
Number 14.
[56:14]  But only a few from the later generations.
And this again tells us that, you know, just the later it
gets, the harder it is for people to understand and to follow.
And they're so bogged down by the material things of this life that it's too hard for them to be religious and to do five daily Prayers, and, or fast for a month.
They couldn't see that at all.
And, and so it seems like it is harder.
And I guess now we have all the Prayer and
we have all the five commandments.
And it is. It's more, I don't know what you wanna call
it, technical or something to get.
There's more work maybe to get to the Highest
Heaven.
And it's harder for those people who wanna work that hard and wanna put in the time to do their Prayers and their fasting and wake up before dawn.
And, and it is harder. And it just seems like those people have to
go through more tests.
And, and it just seems fair in that sense.
God says, they will be
[56:15]  On sturdy furnishings.
They will relax in rows facing each other.
[56:17]  Serving them will be immortal servants.
I know that a lot of these descriptions of the High Heaven or the Low Heaven, maybe even the Hell, they're all allegorical.
And God is, knows us so well that He explains
all these things to us in a way that we could understand.
And so everybody loves to relax and they love
to have stable things around them.
It seems like one day you're down and the
next day you're up.
But, God willing, in Heaven, everything will
just be the same.
And, and it says,
[56:17]  Serving them will be immortal servants.
We'll have people serving us.
Whereas later on we'll find out that in the
Lower Heaven, they have to work for their water.
Naghmeh: They have to pour their own water, whereas we have servants, not we, but people who are in High Heaven.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Naghmeh: I hit two.
Naghmeh: Be in the High Heaven and they will serve
us with cups, pitchers, and pure drinks.
So, it just shows that we're just gonna have to do less work. The more work we do now, the less work we'll do then.
If this, then that.
[56:19]  They are never diverted therefrom, nor deprived.
Which is great because we know that being
here is human and being weak like humans.
We have a tendency to be diverted, but thank
God we're pinched here and there.
And, and we learn.
The ones that wanna learn, they learn.
But we do get diverted. But there, God says "you won't be diverted." And we won't be deprived.
I won't have to look at anyone (unintelligible).
Naghmeh: Wait, what?
Dr. Khalifa: There's a question.
A woman: (unintelligible) that when you said "they won't be
diverted or deprived," doesn't that mean an absence of anything?
Returning to the question of Satan being who diverted Adam
and Eve and deprived them of their garden there.
So, there won't be any Satan in Heaven to
divert you from your reward or deprive you from your credits.
Thank you so much.
[56:20]  With fruits of their choice.
So, whatever we
want.
[56:21]  And meat of birds that they desire.
Anything we choose, anything we desire,
[56:22]  And Magnificent spouses.
We won't have spouses like
we could have on earth, but I guess maybe
it could mean that since people supposedly
love their spouses, then they can love up
there just the same and more.
And, and they won't have to go through any kind
of troubles.
It says that God describes them as precious
pearls.
And, which is, again, wonderful.
[56:24]  This is the recompense of their works.
which shows us that the more righteousness you are
and the more work towards goodness that you do, the better you will be treated in Heaven and the more you can have.
[56:25]  They will hear no vain talk therein, nor sins.
[56:26]  Only utterances of "Peace, peace."
I know that in the Quran it says "believers
should not commit gross sins or they should
stay away from sin," yet God says that He understands
that we do get diverted sometimes.
And it says that we shouldn't sit around tables
where people are talking rumors.
And that if we sit with them, we are just as guilty and
that we should get up and leave.
And if we don't, we stay by mistake, then get
up and leave when you remember and repent.
And that we shouldn't speak behind each other's
backs and things like that.
But I think that a lot of times, especially
when you're in groups of people, things like that,
you do fall into all that. You do fall into rumors.
And it just seems like when people get into
a group, they disagree on so many things.
It's like they say "don't talk about religion.
Don't talk about government. Don't talk about..."
I don't know what else, but don't talk about
rumors.
Because it's the one thing that seems like
a group of people just really understand together.
They really have fun with it.
And they don't have fun if they disagree on
religion.
People wanna kill each other if they talk about government or religion or discrimination or racism or anything like that.
But rumors, it seems like it's an easy topic and it will get people to be friendly with one another and it will pass time.
But up there, we won't have to stoop that
low.
And, and again, Satan won't be there to take us that way and make us forget.
There, there won't be no sin, there will be
no sin, and there will be no vain talk, but
there will be just peace and happiness and,
God willing, we'll be there.
Any questions?
Dr. Khalifa: Verse 13, I have some very good news for you.
I'm not flattering you, but you are very,
very special people.
You've got to go to the Highest, Highest,
Highest Heaven. I'm gonna explain to you why.
When Abraham started the religion of Islam, according to God's instructions, he and the people around him were worshipping God alone.
And as time went by, Satan sneakily and gradually added idol worship until the time of Muhammad came, some centuries later.
By the time Muhammad came, they were worshipping
lots of idols,
Allaat, Manaat, Al-‘Uzzah, and all that. They were
in the Kaaba that Abraham built.
And you've read how many verses in Quran that
say "Abraham was never an idol worshipper."
Yet, there is the Kaaba that he built that
was full of idols.
And then God renewed the message, sent the
Quran to Muhammad.
And sent Muhammad to tell the people "the idols are bad. Worship God alone. Worship God alone." So, what happened?
And Muhammad and his company were persecuted severely.
They threw on them all kinds of dirt and thorns.
Then, they banished them when they grew.
There were about 10 or 15 people for about
3 years.
Then, they grew to about maybe 25 or 30 people.
Then, they thought they were getting too strong,
so they banished them out of Mecca, boycotted them.
Now, and those people were abused.
So, those have to have a special place in Heaven.
They went against the current.
They were worshipping God alone in an ocean
of idolatry.
You can easily see that they were very special
people.
They will be in the highest place in the
High Heaven.
Because even within the High Heaven and the
Low Heaven will be ranks.
Okay, now, 20 years ago, you see how it says
here,
[56:14]  Few from the later generations.
Now, these are later generations after Muhammad.
1400 years after Muhammad.
There is not a single mosque in the Muslim
world that was worshipping God alone,
that was, that is upholding the commandment "the mosque belongs
to God, you should not mention other names with God."
And then God renewed the message right now.
And the message went loud and clear, ringing throughout
the whole world.
"Worship God alone." Say "La Elaha Ella Allah."
NOT "La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasulallah."
And "devote yourselves to God alone. Uphold
the commandments of the Quran."
"Purify your worship. Your Prayer is wrong. Your fasting is wrong. Your zakat is wrong."
These are, these are all blessings from God that He sent
to our generation.
And again, we are subject to the same persecution.
The same ridicule, lucky us.
Yours truly cannot go into any country in the
Middle East. I'll be shot within 24 hours.
It symbolizes this.
And if you go to the Middle East, you better
disown me. I'm asking you to do that.
I mean, God says you even disown God, if you are under
those circumstances.
As long as your heart is filled with faith.
If you don't wanna get in trouble, you better
tell them "I don't know Rashad Khalifa."
But this is...
You are very, very special people.
You've gone through the middle of ridiculing,
and mocking.
Today, Tasneem calls me from New York, and
she was talking to some relatives of hers in
Chicago, who are very active in the so-called
Islamic Center.
And she told them "I'm devoting myself to
God alone. I only say "La Elaha Ella Allah.""
And guess what they said?
They said "Tasneem went to the dogs."
She's worshiping God alone.
And this is ridicule, right? They ridiculed her.
You know "you're saying La Elaha Ella Allah? You're saying, worship God alone? You mean God alone? Is that all you have, God?"
I mean, do you see the logic? They're ridiculing her.
Mahmoud was working the other night.
And some so-called Muslims walked in the store.
And they saw the label that says "Muhammad." Mahmoud on the label.
They said "are you a Muslim?"
He said "yes."
They said "how come we don't see you at the
mosque?"
He said "how come I don't see you at the mosque?"
So, they said "oh, you mean you go to that
mosque?"
That's the mosque that worships God alone,
right?
Now, now, Noah, if you remember in the Quran, Noah
said, because Noah was building the ark with the
flat float, whatever you call it, water raft.
And they were laughing at him. And he told them, he said "you're laughing at me, but I'm really laughing at you."
And this was Mahmoud actually was doing
in the store.
Because they said "oh, we never, we never believe in
mathematics."
A woman: Oh, God.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, this is (unintelligible).
Now on that day, they probably had an exam
in calculus, right?
In university.
And they had to follow the formulas and the
equations, and otherwise they flunk it.
So, they believe in mathematics.
But if it comes to God and the Quran and worshiping
God alone, they don't believe in mathematics.
So, they were looking at Mahmoud, you know,
ridiculing him. And of course, he knows "fool souls."
Just like Noah, he was ridiculing them.
Just like... I mean, he was laughing at them, just like
they were laughing at him.
But this makes Mahmoud a very special person.
This, this is what it means,
[56:13]  Multitudes from the
early generations.
We are the first generation of renewing the
message.
And we see it very clearly. Every one of us is in the light, and we can
see it.
Just go in any mosque in the world and say "La Elaha Ella Allah." They will beat you up.
You are saying "worship God alone."
So, you can see what happens after centuries
from the first generation.
Abraham was the first generation.
And those people, I mean, they threw Abraham
in the fire, right?
In those days, there was no America for Abraham
to run to.
They threw him in the fire. So, what did God do?
He turned the fire into a cool and safe place.
Because God, God says "do not think that I will
abandon my messengers."
God creates exits for them.
So, the exit for Abraham was a cool and safe
fire.
And the people who were with him, they were
persecuted.
They have to be special people. Because the easiest thing is to go along with the masses, with the crowds.
You think this shook Mahmoud?
Not one hair.
And this is why he's very special.
I'm just using Mahmoud as an example.
Muhtesem went to a grocery store to buy
some Middle Eastern stuff.
And he met some Arabs there.
They're just totally ignorant. They know nothing.
But he says "yes, we go to Masjid Tucson. We worship God alone."
And they almost beat him up.
If he wasn't big enough and strong enough,
and a Turk, they would have beaten him up.
So, why do you have to take all this abuse
and all this ridicule? Do you think it shook him up?
Did it affect his faith?
If anything, it strengthened his faith.
Because he knows that those people are wrong.
He knows they're ignorant. He knows they're not worshipping God alone. He knows they lost their Prayer. Probably, never Pray.
Those people, do you think they Pray?
Muhtesem: Well, I asked them "how many Suras are in the
Quran?"
Dr. Khalifa: What? They don't know?
Dr. Khalifa: You don't know?
Muhtesem: (unintelligible)
They would say "you're going to Hell."
I said "(unintelligible)
(unintelligible). He was Palestinian.
Muhtesem: "You're going to Hell."
Dr. Khalifa: And he doesn't know how many Suras are in the Quran.
Muhtesem: (unintelligible) on the Day of Judgement (unintelligible)
Muhtesem: Yet he was there (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: God is telling you "I'm with you."
Muhtesem: (unintelligible)
Muhtesem: He's miserable. Just because I worship (unintelligible). I worship God alone.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Muhtesem: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's the abuse and ridicule that all of
you went through, all of you, every single one of you.
Muhtesem: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The Bashar couple, the Bashars, they ridiculed
them so many times.
"You mean you go to that mosque."
And the answer is "show me a place where they
worship God alone, and I'll go."
"We'll go to that place."
I will go to that place. Any place where they worship God alone, we'll
go.
God is the One... God is the One who created you.
God is the One who provides for you.
God is the One who controls your health, your
welfare.
God is the One who controls your happiness.
God is the only One who controls your success.
Muhammad is dead. The saints are dead. Jesus is dead. Powerless. Even when they were alive. They had absolutely no power.
So, I mean they just...
Because you're going through... This is a first generation. We are.
We are so lucky.
We are a first generation, just like Abraham's
generation, Muhammad's generation.
Muhammad's generation went through the ridicule,
the abuse, and they had to leave their city, Mecca, and go to Medina.
The persecution they went through. Because of this, God reserves a special place for them.
God is reserving a special place for us. I'm saying it by God's grace.
So, I have this very good news for you.
Because you are... you fit here in verse 13.
[56:13]  Multitudes from the early generations.*
In 50 years, I assure you, in 50 years, there'll be millions of people worshipping God alone, and upholding the Quran alone,
and Praying the correct way.
Millions. In just 50 years.
But they will be following the crowd.
They cannot be like you.
They will be protected by their numbers.
Right at this location, right here, there'll be thousands, on this block, in this mosque.
And there'll be powerful... the people jumping
on the wagons.
But they don't deserve the same position,
or the same credit as you.
So, this is, this is what it means.
[56:13]  Multitudes from the early generations.*
[56:14]  But only a few from the last generations.
Because these are the far ahead, in Arabic,
(56:10) ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ
These will be the closest to God. They're very special.
That's you.
And you start collecting benefits now.
And we've seen it. We have a history already. We have a track record in this mosque,
10 years of a track record, a perfect track record, in this life.
It's guaranteed by God.
We may have a pinch here and there, but it's
because we make mistakes.
The tests are brief for you. But if you stray
off the path, you know you're gonna get a pinch.
And you get the pinch and say "thank you God." And come back to the path.
You are very special people.
You deserve a lot of congratulations.
God says in Sura 35 that the angels have
wings, 2, 3, and 4.
2, 3, and 4, because the angels closest to
God will be the most powerful, the highest in rank.
They have more wings. This is figuratively speaking.
And these
(56:10) ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ
these far ahead people, like yourselves, will be there.
I mean, all those are angels, but still, they have ranks.
And 50 years from now, the thousands of people
who will be in this location, IN SHAA ALLAH,
they will go to the High Heaven, because they worship
God alone, and they will Pray the correct way.
And they'll go to the High Heaven, but they
cannot attain your rank.
Because you're the ones who are taking the
abuse.
The people who take the abuse and the ridicule
have a very special position in the Bible and in the Quran.
I had a little thing, they hang in there for
a while, that says "Congratulations to those who are persecuted."
For the prophets also have been persecuted. Remember that verse?
They hang it there.
And this is God telling you "Congratulations."
So, we are very, very lucky. And I'm stressing, I keep stressing this,
because I cannot stress it enough.
Just so you can thank God, so you can be appreciative,
so you know who you are.
Satan will always put doubts in your mind, always will tell you "you're nobody." He hates your guts, okay?
Because he's gonna be deep, deep in Hell.
You hear that, Iman? You were asking about Satan in the Hereafter. He will not be in Heaven, No.
He will not even come close.
He and his troops will be way deep down in
the lowest pit of Hell.
And he'll be beating them, and they'll be
beating him.
They're gonna spend eternity doing that.
So, he will try to tell you "you're a nobody." But you speak, you speak back to him. Tell him "I believe God."
And I believe that I am in this group.
[56:13]  Multitudes from the early generations.*
Because this is the first generation.
I mean, I couldn't believe it myself.
For a long time, I said "it couldn't be just
us here worshipping God alone. There must be millions in the world."
But I discovered that I'm naive, that the human being is really bad.
I was talking to my nephew, Sharif, in Egypt.
And he said "I'm the only one in Egypt."
He really is a believer.
And you can tell the, you can tell the people who believe because they are in the light. They understand.
And he's the only one that I know in Egypt, that's really a believer.
IN SHAA ALLAH, he will come to the conference.
He's only, he's only 20.
He was born two weeks before Beth.
And he's the only believer in all of Egypt.
I mean, I was really naive.
I mean I said "there must be millions in Egypt who
worship God alone."
Nope. Wrong.
So, this is why I'm speaking so strongly.
I'm telling you "you're very special."
And when Satan tells you "you're not," you tell
him to shut up.
You're very special.
That is the verse that talks about you.
Congratulations.
Dr. Sabahi: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And this time, and this time, right now.
It refers to Muhammad's time, Ibrahim's time,
and this time, our time.
We are a first generation.
Right now.
Because we are the fortunate generation that is renewing God's message, restoring it, cleaning out all the junk and innovations.
When you go back to Iran for a visit, you'll be... which town you will be in?
Dr. Khalifa: Tehran?
Dr. Sabahi: Tehran.
Dr. Khalifa: I think you'll be the only one in Tehran who's praying the correct way, you and (unintelligible), the kids.
You'll be the only... and they laugh at you.
When you tell them "and in TASHAHUD I just say the name of
God alone,
they say "you mean, you don't mention Muhammad or Ahlul-Bayt or Ali?"
"No."
See, this is what we cleaned out,
cleaned out all the creatures. We just mention the Creator.
And this is restoring the religion. Soو you are a first generation.
Does this make you special or not? When you're the only one in Tehran who's Praying the correct way. Tehran is how many millions? Five?
You can see the details but this circle here, you start on this side.
You put down the first, start with the first verse of Quran.
And write the number of every verse in Quran.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
The first Sura is 7 verses.
Then, put 7, the number of verses in the Sura.
And then do the same with every Sura all the way to the end of Quran, only in the upper half.
And then...
Ok. Let me do it the other way around. Start with the number of verses in the Sura, 7.
Then, the number of each verse. 1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7.
And then you will link with the other system where
you put the verses first and then the number later.
Ok. You will end up with a number that is in a circle
that is 25,400 approximately digits, numbers.
This number is one mile long.
And it is divisible by 19 and it has all the
numbers in the Quran with the two systems.
One system where you put the number of verses
at the end of the list of verses.
Another system, you put the total number of
verses at the beginning.
And in between the two systems, you have the
number of the verses in the whole Quran.
It's gonna be in the circle.
This eventually is going to convert the whole world because they will know that this book is not human made.
I mean the miracles are becoming so strong
now that they will be irresistible.
So, we may be a very special... you're still a very special group, generation because you've been here even before this miracle was half this strong.
It is growing now.
And 50 years from now, it's gonna be very
common knowledge.
People will accept it easier because there'll be more people talking about it.
These people told Mahmoud "we don't believe
in mathematics." They didn't even look at it.
But as they jump in the wagon, they will look
at it and they will see it and they will know.
They will just believe. They will know that
this is God's message to the world.
So, the later generations for us may be different
from the others.
Dr. Khalifa: There are only 300 years left.
Dr. Sabahi: As if God is saying that (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This has been the system. You see, Christianity was corrupted 300 years after Jesus.
I mean, totally corrupted.
They had the Nicene Conferences and they invented
the Trinity and everything, 300 years after Jesus.
With Muhammad, it was 300 years that the Hadith became recorded and Islam was wiped out, totally corrupted 300 years after Muhammad.
Now with our generation, when it is 300 years,
it's gonna be the end of the world.
And this is documented here in the Quran.
So, we have a special situation here.
Also, we have a verse in Quran in 41:53 that says,
[41:53]  We will show them our signs in the horizons, and within themselves, until they realize that this is the truth.
So, this is a prophecy that God gave us.
And this is what's happening now. And it will take 300 years for the world to realize,
probably every single person on earth will realize that this is God's message to the world.
And I suspect the world will end with
only believers on earth.
That's when Satan will throw up his hands
and say "I give up. I have no constituents anymore."
And that will be the end, end of the test.
The miracle is very powerful.
And this is the very reason why you are very
special people because you believed from the very beginning.
Some of you, even without looking at the miracle, you agreed to worship God alone and uphold the Quran alone.
That's a very special situation.
Dr. Khalifa: I stole the show from Naghmeh.
Naghmeh: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: I thought it was very important. I wanted you to know who you are.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: Does it mean that there is also stratification within this...
Dr Khalifa: Yes, within each (unintelligible), yes.
A man: (unintelligible) sorry.
Dr. Khalifa: But you can call this Hell. And there'll be (unintelligible) there in the deepest... The hypocrites will be in the deepest pit of Hell.
Hypocrites are people who think they are believers. They say they're believers. They believe they are believers. But they are not.
Those are the hypocrites.
But the whole place is Hell. This is what...
And God says "those who barely miss Hell and
make it into the lowest layer of the Purgatory"
God calls this "a fantastic triumph."
Because if you miss this, this thing called Hell,
within which there are different layers.
The same with the Lower Heaven and the same
with the High Heaven.
Because the people in the Purgatory, they
cannot go much higher, but they are fantastically happy.
They are in Heaven.
And within Heaven, like I said, there will
be a line beyond which you cannot go.
These are natural borders.
Your growth and development will decide that.
You know, every time you get abused and ridiculed,
you grow immensely.
That's why Mahmoud came out smiling out of
that episode.
So that Muhtesem... Gatut comes across those ones in a while.
A woman: I have one right in law school.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: He's not going to law school, but he works
in a library. One time he went like this. It was like almost he hit me.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: He was...and he...
Dr. Khalifa: Does he worship God alone, right?
A woman: And he was like, he was like "Dr. Khalifa says that it's
OK for you to repent. Muslims don't have the right to repent."
A woman: I was like "Excuse me?!"
That's exactly what he said. He said "God doesn't tell us we have the right to repent. And he tells us that you can repent a hundred times."
A woman: And I'm like "of course, you can. Without repenting, we'll all go to Hell. Are you kidding?"
Dr. Khalifa: But that's in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: I guess he never read the Quran.
A woman: Oh, so many other things.
And he's like "you need a Muslim husband who
will teach you how it is."
And I said "I'll teach him how it is."
So, yes, I beat him, too.
Dr. Khalifa: That's what he needs.
A woman: I said "I'll teach him."
Dr. Khalifa: That's our love.
A woman: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Let me tell you the kind of ridicule and the
kind of stupidity they have. I have it obtained here.
This fellow came from Denver, Colorado.
And he wants to talk to me. So, I said 'if you have any place for us to talk, we'll talk to you."
And I said.... anyway, the conversation ended by me challenging him to say "La Elaha Ella Allah."
I'm really convinced they cannot do it.
I mean, I really know this now. Ihsan was listening.
I told him "you are forbidden by God from
saying La Elaha Ella Allah."
He said "are you crazy or something? Of course, I can say La Elaha Ella Allah."
I said "go ahead. Say it."
I said "say it." Remember?
And he will say "La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasulallah."
I said "see? You cannot say it. Can you?"
He said "of course, I can say it."
I said "go ahead. Say it."
He said "La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasulallah."
I said "see? You just proved to me that you cannot say
La Elaha Ella Allah, can you? Because you are forbidden by God."
I mean, here I'm challenging this guy to
say "La Elaha Ella Allah," and he cannot say it.
I have it all recorded from the thing.
Now, so, this is, this is a fellow I kept challenging,
and again, I guess he got so mad, so half hour later,
he called and he said "I'm gonna bring the gun and kill you tonight."
Yeah, I have it. I have it on tape.
So, now he's so stupid because he talks at the machine, we're recording it, along with his phone number and everything.
So, of course, we called the police. The police went and paid him a visit.
But that's how, that's how stupid, how angry
he gets.
Would you threaten somebody and record it
on the machine?
His address was divisible by 19.
But this is the kind of abuse, the kind of ridiculing that every time you go through this, you grow immensely. This is a very special treat to you.
If Naghmeh and Apamea did not have the courage, they would have quit long time ago.
I mean, from cousins to brothers to uncles,
relatives, aunts, everywhere, friends.
They're ridiculing them. Look at them, steady,
persevering.
(unintelligible)
God takes the believers
out of darkness into the light.
And how can you go back to darkness after you've lived in the light?
They cannot say "La Elaha Ella Allah." (unintelligible).
I know they are forbidden by God from saying it.
They are hypnotized by Satan or whatever the (unintelligible) is.
So, within the High Heaven, there are ranks. And within the Lower Heaven, there are ranks. And within Hell, there are ranks.
But these are the general divisions.
As we saw in Sura 55, there are big differences
between the High Heaven and the Lower Heaven.
But what we have seen are the general characteristics.
Dr. Khalifa: Congratulations.
Dr. Sabahi: Can I ask a question?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Sabahi: Is it (unintelligible) Quran that (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, there will be, there will be more believers than ever now.
By the way, some people that were kind of suspicious
of my population.
And God never let me down.
(unintelligible) Magazine, the last issue, had an article
of the population.
They had a population curve there.
It is in full agreement with my history.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is good.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: ...the growing generations including us with a bar?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Because I showed that the people from now to the end of the world will be 15 times as many as the people from the beginning of Adam until now.
In other words, the vast majority of the human race are getting the message that our generation is beginning right now.
Or starting a message of worshipping God alone,
upholding God's Word alone.
And this is the message that God wills for
the vast majority of the human race.
70 billion people.
See, until now we had 6 billion people.
From now to the end of the world, it is projected
that we'll have 70 billion people.
But to answer Dr. Sabahi's question, the verse
in the Quran says,
it doesn't say that everyone will be a believer, but it says "I will show
them My signs until they realize that this is the truth."
So, the prophecy is that God will spread His signs until everybody becomes a...
Not everybody, maybe everybody, but at least
almost everybody will be a believer.
The miracles that we are seeing now, and they
have all discovered the people connected with us.
The people who believe exactly as we do.
And this is an exclusive, specifically a very
strong sign.
And these miracles will be known by everyone.
I'm telling you, in 50 years, there'll be millions, millions of people worshipping God alone and following the Quran alone.
Millions, in just 50 years, maybe less.
Naghmeh: You know, what I was gonna say also, it's
not only that we're gonna have more people
later who are gonna be seeing these miracles,
but also there's another mercy I think from God in that
the old generation, there might
not have been as many people as we're gonna have.
But the life span then was, what,
35 or 40 years old. Women died in labor.
Naghmeh: There was the wars between Spain and, you know, the Europe and stuff. They were all young people.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Naghmeh: And so, you know, it seems like there was mercy there
too, because they were all young and they died young.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Naghmeh: Yeah. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Naghmeh: Okay, The Lower Heaven, 27.
[56:27]  As for the inhabitants of the right side, they will be on the right side.
[56:28]  They will enjoy lush orchards.
[56:29]  And fresh fruits.
[56:30]  And abundant shade.
[56:31]  And water to be poured.
[56:32]  And many fruits.
[56:33]  Always in season.
[56:34]  And exalted furnishings.
[56:35]  We raise spouses for them.
[56:36]  Never previously touched.
[56:37]  Magnificent companions.
[56:38]  Exclusively reserved for inhabitants of the right side.
[56:39]  Multitudes from the early generation.
[56:40]  And multitudes from the later generations.
Okay, number 27.
This we see, the difference between this is
from the far ahead to the right side.
And, you know, we've said it over and over again. Well, we
know that the people who died before the age of 40
go in the Lower Heaven. And we know that
the basic rules in the Quran to make the Lower Heaven is
to believe in God alone, to work
righteousness, and to believe in the Hereafter.
And those people will make it.
Then, then the right side just sounds so right, sounds
so right.
Because first of all, like we know from, you know, the (unintelligible) that we always play is that God knows everything.
God knows the one who is really, really, really
mean and bad and He will keep them until they're old.
But, but the ones who died before they are 40,
obviously God knew that there was something right about them.
And just because, you know, their life was shorter than ours doesn't mean that it was any kind of bad, you know, thing from God's position.
But that maybe they were gonna prove a
test for their family or whatever.
But that the thing is that God knew they were
on the right side.
And God tells us that the age of 40, you know,
before the age of 40, they go to the Lower Heaven.
And, and it just makes sense that those are the people who died before that age. And plus, it's a test for their families.
But they are still, they're so protected.
And so if you're on the right side here, you'll
be on the right side there.
You won't be up at the top of the people who
really tried hard.
But you'll be there. And also I think a lot of times, you know, there are a lot of people who believe in God alone.
They believe in the Hereafter and they work
righteousness.
But it's just way too difficult to ask them
to do anything else.
They might give to charity but, you know, on
their own, a lot of people maybe do.
But they probably don't even give money or
anything, but old clothes type of things.
Naghmeh: But...
Dr. Khalifa: God says He will reward them for their
righteousness.
Naghmeh: Right.
You know, so it's some kind of charity. But they will not do the Prayer. It's too hard.
They say "I can see myself doing one but five",
you know. And...
And, and I'm like "you're not doing any, you know,
God doesn't need you to be doing this. It's for us."
You know, "and you're not doing any favors
for God for doing your prayer, but that it's a favor for us."
And over all that, to think 25 minutes maybe
out of your whole day, 24 hours, is really nothing.
And I hate to think of it as that but sometimes it just brings you down just saying that.
But anyways...
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
A woman: I know.
Naghmeh: So, but I guess they're just right on...
Dr. Khalifa: The Prayers, the Prayers are meals. When they say "one Prayer maybe but not five", this means, it's like saying, I just have breakfast.
Naghmeh: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Nothing else.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) But whatever righteous thing, work you do, you get rewards.
Again, we're gonna hear some allegorical
things.
There's gonna be some difference from the
Highest Heaven.
There's gonna be shade and there's gonna be fresh fruits, but it doesn't say what they choose.
It doesn't say what they desire but there
will be fresh fruits.
And it says,
[56:31]  And water to be poured.
which means poured, I guess, from them because it doesn't say that they will have servants.
So, that means a little bit more work for those
people.
But they will be taken care of, basically.
I don't understand why it says here
[56:35]  We raise spouses for them.
But in the other one, it says that they will
automatically have, like, you know, magnificent spouses.
What's the difference between raising spouses
for the right...?
Dr. Khalifa: It's like, if you can go to the market and get a meal of corn, or you can put a seed in there and watch it grow until it's a tree of corn.
Naghmeh: Oh, that is great.
I mean, it makes sense.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that's a little bit different.
Naghmeh: That is great.
Naghmeh: And here we have multitudes from the early
generations and multitudes from the later generations,
which goes along with what you were just saying, that in the later generations that come after the people who went through all the
trouble and the hassles, the people laughing at them and mocking them, there will be a lot of people who will be, God willing, following the scripture.
The footnote says "because all the humans who die as children will be assigned to the Lower Heaven, the proportion from each generation is about the same.
That also makes sense, of course.
So, we just know that, you know, multitudes from the early
generations, that could be the people, you know, who,
Naghmeh: the younger, yeah,
Dr. Khalifa: Children, Children.
Naghmeh: the ones who died before the age of 40, because in the earlier generations, they died at a young age, and then the multitudes from the later generations could be the ones, all the people who follow us.
Dr. Khalifa: But because this happens all the time, no matter what is happening, it could be Abraham's generation, or Muhammad's generation, all the generations, but still, children die in accidents,
people die before 40. So, this is happening
continuously.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So, 40 is there.
Naghmeh: Yeah. Any questions about the Lower Heaven?
How?
41.
Hell goes right after 41!
Wait, what?
It's 41!
Naghmeh: My God.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Oh, my God.
Naghmeh: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: This (unintelligible) Huh?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yep.
Dr. Khalifa: 41 means Hell, if you don't make that
decision.
A woman: Oh, wait a minute.
Dr. Khalifa: If you don't make that decision by then...
A woman: Ok.
A woman: That's the year (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: 41 is higher.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Naghmeh: Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: Remember the circle?
See, this circle here means every verse in the Quran
is numbered according to a system, God's system.
Naghmeh: As for the...should I go on?
[56:41]  As for the inhabitants of the left, they will be on the left.
If you don't work righteousness, you don't
believe in God alone, you don't do the commandments,
you don't listen to your inner intuition to
believe in God and work righteousness, then
you will be exactly where you deserve to be,
which is Hell, which is...
Dr. Khalifa: Lisa wants to stop you.
Naghmeh: Oh, I'm sorry.
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Lisa: If you go to the Sura that we looked at last week, it talks about Hell.
Naghmeh: It's 41!
A man: Oh, my God.
A woman: Oh, my God.
Naghmeh: Mã Shã Allãh
A woman: What page?
Dr. Khalifa: 378. 378.
Dr. Khalifa: There is no doubt.
There'll be no doubt, folks, about the age of 40.
Age 40 is the cut-off point.
Naghmeh: We're like the people on Noah's Ark.
Naghmeh: Or people walking through the sea, you
know, with Moses. God, we're just like those people.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Naghmeh: [56:42]  In ill winds and retribution.
[56:43]  In shade that actually burns.
[56:44]  Never cool, never tolerable.
[56:45]  They used to be spoiled.
[56:46]  They insisted on the great blasphemy.
[56:47]  They used to say, "After we die and become dust and bones, do we get resurrected?
[56:48]  "Even our early ancestors."
[56:49]  Say, "The early generations and the late generations.
[56:50]  "Will be gathered together on a predetermined day.
[56:51]  "Then you, O strayers and disbelievers.
[56:52]  "Will eat from the trees of bitterness.
[56:53]  "You will fill your bellies therefrom.
[56:54]  "Then you will top it with lava.
[56:55]  "You will ingest drinks of humiliation."
[56:56]  Such is their position on the Day of Judgment.
[56:57]  We created you, if you could only believe!
[56:58]  Do you see the semen you produce?
[56:59]  Is it you who create it, or are we the creators?
[56:60]  We have designed death for you. And nothing can prevent us—
[56:61]  from substituting others in your place, and establishing what you do not know.
I stop there.
Again, if you don't work righteousness and
believe in God alone and everything, then
you will be in Hell where you deserve to be.
Again, allegorically, I believe, it very graphically
explains to us what it's going to be like in Hell.
And I don't have to be there to already feel
it.
And...
And it says that ill winds and retribution.
And they will be constantly burning. And they
can just never get out.
And...
And just it seems sad in a way, but again, you know, God
has just put Hell, created Hell, and we put ourselves in there.
And God knows and in every scripture it's described
what Hell is gonna be like.
And people just don't understand. They don't believe in it.
[56:45]  They used to be spoiled.
[56:46]  They insisted on the great blasphemy.
[56:47]  They used to say, "After we die and become dust and bones, do we get resurrected?
[56:45]  They used to be spoiled.
That seems like such a, you know, good word again, spoiled.
Besides, it seems like the people who just wanna
be in control and the people who just think that
material things make them happy and if they're down, well, you know, "it's okay honey, let's go shopping" or whatever.
Actually...
Wait, wait, wait.
Dr. Khalifa: Believers can do that, too.
(unintelligible)
Naghmeh: I take that back.
I said "thank you, God."
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Naghmeh: How can I say thank you?
Well, anyway, those spoiled people who think that they're just in charge and that they can make things better or worse on their own
and they don't need anyone else or anything else and, you know, as long as they have everything that they like in this life, then it's fine and...
and they don't have to question the Hereafter. They don't feel that there's anything holding them back for them to be seeking God.
It's like a lot of people, you know, when they go through a bad time, it's when they go towards God and it says it in the Quran. It says.
"Whenever hard times come to them, they remember Me. When things get better, they forget about Me."
Dr. Khalifa: It's called Bad Weather Friends.
A woman: Bad Weather Friends.
Dr. Khalifa: In the new translation, Bad weather friends.
Cause when they are about to drown or the plane
is in trouble, they remember God.
(unintelligible) this verse is saying.
As soon as they land on shore, they forget
God.
Naghmeh: And they just insist on the great blasphemy no matter how many times maybe hardship falls upon them, how many times they get stuck in the
black sea or whatever, they still might go back.
Well, the people who are in Hell, they do,
but some people learn from their mistakes.
And they question "after we die and become
dust and bones, do we get resurrected?"
So many people have troubles with that.
About... they'll believe in maybe reincarnation.
I went to this comedy club the other day. I have never gone to one before.
And so many times they talked about Shirley
MacLaine saying that she's gonna be...
Naghmeh: She was in reincarnation.
A woman: She'll be back.
Naghmeh: She'll be back.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Naghmeh: She was, she was an elephant or something.
In the Hereafter, but she will not believe that she could... her soul could be raised. But she'll believe in reincarnation.
And so many of these people brought up the
same thing, you know, up on the stage.
And...
Anyway, so they question that, too.
And God says "if you don't believe in the Hereafter,"
one of the pillars of the Lower Heavens, then that's it.
[56:48]  "Even our early ancestors."
There's no difference. We know that God has sent us prophets and
messengers throughout the community and throughout our lives.
So, whether it's early ancestors or later ancestors,
we're all gonna be resurrected together no matter what.
[56:49]  Say, "The early generations and the late generations.
like what I said.
[56:50]  "Will be gathered together on a predetermined day.
We know that, well, we know that the Day of Resurrection, the Day of Judgment will come in about 300 years.
And that...
And that everybody will be waiting in line
and they will be judged by their souls and their videotapes.
And we're all gonna be together. We're all gonna see what the other person is and there's nothing you can hide.
And like it says in the Quran, it says, even, you know, the ones who are friends will be hating each other on that day, you know when,
if they didn't work righteousness.
So, all will be together.
[56:51]  "Then you, O strayers and disbelievers.
[56:52]  "Will eat from the trees of bitterness.
[56:53]  "You will fill your bellies therefrom. [56:54]  "Then you will top it with lava. [56:55]  "You will ingest drinks of humiliation."
which again describes everything that they go through
and how miserable it would be where your soul
is not developed.
[56:56]  Such is their position on the Day of Judgment.
[56:57]  We created you, if you could only believe!
[56:58]  Do you see the semen you produce?
[56:59]  Is it you who create it, or are we the creators?
Again, you know, this is another reminder again for
us to take a look at. Gosh, you know, how were we created?
How did all this come about, you know?
And it's just incredible how the whole system
of, I guess, getting pregnant or whatever works.
And it's just really amazing. And if somebody doesn't question where that came from, they think that it came from generations of monkeys,
then I think there's something
wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: Did anybody see Nova?
(unintelligible)
They were talking about this, had a program on this.
Dr. Khalifa: how the semens come and move to their position.
Naghmeh: Only one out of...
Dr. Khalifa: If anybody sees that who does not believe in
God...
I can't imagine anybody watching this and
not believing in God.
That was a few days ago.
Naghmeh: Just how perfect every single woman's body work. I mean, it's just amazing.
And God questions it, you know, is it you who created it? Is it the prophets who came down? Is it the messengers who created it?